<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<animals>
    <item>fish
        <name>Common Clownfish</name>
        <scientific>Amphiprion ocellaris</scientific>
        <id>1</id>
        <Habitat>Amphiprion ocellaris inhabits coral reefs (Allen 1997) and sheltered lagoons up to a depth of 15 meters. More specifically, it is mainly found in or near the anemones Heteractis magnifica, Stichodactyla gigantean, and Stichodactyla mertensii (Myers 1999) as part of a symbiotic relationship.</Habitat>
        <Physical>False clownfish are orange to reddish-brown with three white bands on the head and body. The white bands are outlined in black. Black A. ocellaris, with white bands and black coloring instead of orange, are found off the Northern Territory of Australia. Amphiprion ocellaris has a rounded caudal fin and may grow up to 110 mm in length. There are 11 dorsal spines and 17 pectoral rays that help to distinguish it from the closely related Amphiprion percula. Females are larger than males in this species. </Physical>
        <Diet>Planktonic food such as zooplankton, copepods, and algae are the primary source of food for A. ocellaris. They are classified as generalized omnivores as they feed on equal amounts of algae and animals. They are also reported to consume parasites from their host anemones. Feeding is also dominated by the hierarchical structure of the group dynamics in the anemone. Because the smaller fish receive the most aggression from the others, they have reduced energy for foraging great distances from the anemone and tend to stay close. Additionally, it is unsafe for the smaller fish to stray farther from the safety of the anemone. The large, dominant fish will forage at greater distances, but generally no farther than several meters from the anemone.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Lifespan has not been studied fully in the wild, but it is believed that A. ocellaris may live 6-10 years. Larval fish are extremely susceptible to predation as they have no way of defending themselves and have high mortality rates. Captivity transfer experiments have been performed to address the possibility of restocking the fish in areas where they have been depleted; these find that survival among transferred fish is higher among smaller A. ocellaris.</Lifespan>
    </item>

    <item>fish
        <name>Tiger Shark</name>
        <scientific>Galeocerdo cuvier</scientific>
        <id>2</id>
        <Habitat>Tiger sharks are found in many subtropical and tropical waters, primarily from 45°N to 32°S. Tiger sharks have been sighted from the eastern coast of North America to the eastern coast of Brazil. This includes the coasts of southern North America, Mexico, and Latin America along the Gulf of Mexico. Tiger sharks also populate the coasts of China, India, Africa, Japan, and many islands of the Pacific Ocean.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Tiger sharks are one of the largest carnivores in the ocean. Juveniles have tiger-like stripes, which fade as they grow older. Tiger sharks are blue or green in color with a light yellow or white under-belly. This speices has a large blunt nose on the end of a wedge-shaped head. Tiger sharks have serrated teeth, making it easy to tear flesh and crack the bones and shells of their prey. They have a heterocercal tail, meaning the dorsal lobe of the caudal fin is longer than the ventral lobe. Adults range from 3.25 to 4.25 m in length, although tiger sharks of 6 to 7.5 m in length have been documented. Female tiger sharks are on average 2.92 m in length and are smaller than males, which are on average 3.20 m in length. Adult tiger sharks typically weigh 385 to 635 kg, with largest sharks reaching 862 kg.</Physical>
        <Diet>The diet of tiger sharks includes mollusks, birds, snakes, crustaceans, sea turtles, and dugongs. Serrated teeth give this species the ability to penetrate the shells of sea turtles. Tiger sharks often scavenge dead or injured whales, and large tiger sharks can survive several weeks without feeding. This species most likely relies on stealth rather than strength and speed to catch prey. They are well camouflaged, allowing them to get within striking range of prey. If prey flee, tiger sharks may back off, not taking part in high-speed pursuits. However, tiger sharks are capable of short bursts of speed once their prey are within range.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>The average lifespan of tiger sharks in the wild is 27 years, though some may live to 50 years of age. Tiger sharks in captivity do not live as long, a maximum of 17 to 20 years. In captivity, this species tends to die of starvation rather than old age, as food that is already dead is less appealing to tiger sharks.</Lifespan>
    </item>

    <item>fish
        <name>Redbelly Piranha</name>
        <scientific>Pygocentrus nattereri</scientific>
        <id>3</id>
        <Habitat>Pygocentrus nattereri is found in South America. Pygocentrus nattereri can be found east of the Andes in the Parana-Paraguay and Amazon basin. They can also be found in rivers of northeast Brazil and the Guianas.They are typically found in whitewater streams in South America. However, the species is not found typically in blackwater streams</Habitat>
        <Physical>Pygocentrus nattereri physical characteristics vary with location, population, and age. In juvenile P. nattereri there are differences in physical characteristics depending on the size of the fish. A change in color pattern does seem to develop as size increases. The thickening body tissue tends to cause the black internal line of the anal fin to disappear and both the number of body spots and the density of melanophores increases with growth. Adult specimens also tend to vary in color pattern and body size with geographic location. Generally P. nattereri is reddish-orange ventrally and silver-gray dorsally. The fins vary in color as well, with a black dorsal fin, black anal fin, and reddish-orange pectoral fins. The lateral color of the fish is a gray to silver- gray.</Physical>
        <Diet>Foraging methods vary in different life stages of P. nattereri. During the day, smaller fish (80-110 mm) search for food. At dawn, late afternoon, and early evening the larger fish (150-240 mm) search for food. Pygocentrus nattereri groups gather in vegetation in order to wait for prey. The group typically includes around 20-30 fishes. In the daytime P. nattereri can be seen lurking or ambushing prey. Two other methods for obtaining food employed by P. nattereri are chasing and scavenging. The hunting mode of chasing was seen after the fish lie and wait in vegetation. The fish then proceed to swim after and eat the fish. P. nattereri has a wide variety of food in its diet, including fins, scales, fish (pieces and whole), insects, snails, and plants. The plant intake of the animal may be an active way of gaining food supplies while scanning for prey.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Piranhas can live up to eight years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>fish
        <name>Atlantic Sailfish</name>
        <scientific>Istiophorus platypterus</scientific>
        <id>4</id>
        <Habitat>Indo-Pacific sailfish (Istiophorus platypterus) can be found in both temperate and tropical waters throughout the world's oceans. They generally have a tropical distribution and are particularly abundant near the equatorial regions of the Atlantic, Pacific, and Indian Oceans from 45° to 50° N in the western North Pacific and from 35° to 40° N in the eastern North Pacific to approximately 35° S in the eastern South Pacific. In the western Indian Ocean and in the eastern Indian Ocean, Indo-Pacific sailfish range between 45° to 35° S, respectively. This species is essentially found along the coastal regions of these latitudes, but can also be found in the central regions of these oceans.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Trophy specimens of Indo-Pacific sailfish have measured up to 340 cm, weighing as much as 100 kg. Their fusiform body is long, compressed, and remarkably streamlined. Indo-Pacific sailfish are dark blue dorsally, with a mix of brown and light blue laterally, and a silver-white color on their ventral side. This coloration is a form of obliterative countershading. This species is easily distinguished from other billfish by the approximately 20 stripes of light blue dots present along their lateral sides. Their head bears a long bill and jaws filled with file-like teeth. Their massive first dorsal fin is sail-like, with 42 to 49 rays, with a much smaller second dorsal fin, with 6 to 7 rays. The pectoral fins are long, stiff, and falcate in shape, bearing 18 to 20 rays. Pelvic fins are thoracic in position and up to 10 cm in length. Scale size decreases with maturity and scales are nearly absent in adults. Members of this species are exceptional swimmers, with a minute drag coefficient range of 0.0075 to 0.0091, which allows individuals to reach burst speeds of up to 110 km/hr. At cruising speeds of 11 km/hr, they can fold down their first dorsal fin to reduce drag.</Physical>
        <Diet>Typical foods of Indo-Pacific sailfish are epipelagic fish such as mackerels, sardines, and anchovies, as well as cephalopods. Sailfish been observed at cruising speeds with their dorsal fins folded back halfway in pursuit of prey. When sailfish attack a school of fish, they fold their fin back completely, achieving attack speeds of up to 110 km/hr. Once they approach their prey, they turn their bill quickly and hit the prey, stunning or killing it. Indo-Pacific sailfish either hunt alone or in small groups. Aside from hunting schools of small fish, Indo-Pacific sailfish are also opportunistic feeders, occasionally preying on neritic and benthic prey, a behavior similar to other billfish such as blue marlin, swordfish, and striped marlin. The particular species eaten by Indo-Pacific sailfish depend on the spatio-temporal distribution of their prey populations. Remnants of cephalopod and fish mandibles found in their stomachs suggest the rapid digestion of soft muscles.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Indo-Pacific sailfish have an estimated maximum lifespan of 13 to 15 years; however, the average age of catch and release specimens is 4 to 5 years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>fish
        <name>Great Hammerhead Shark</name>
        <scientific>Sphyrna mokarran</scientific>
        <id>5</id>
        <Habitat>Great hammerhead sharks occur in all tropical waters worldwide. These sharks are found in both open ocean and shallow coastal waters. During summer they may make small migrations towards more northerly areas.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Great hammerhead sharks posses a virtually straight anterior margin of the head with a deep central indentation. They have high second dorsal fins and the pelvic fins have curved rear margins. The teeth are triangular with extraordinarily serrated edges, becoming increasingly oblique toward the corners of the mouth. Their coloration varies from deep olive green to brownish grey above and white below. They are generally 4 to 6 m in length.</Physical>
        <Diet>Great hammerhead sharks feed on rays, smaller sharks, and many species of bony fishes.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>The typical lifespan of this species is 20–30 years; the record Boca Grande female was estimated to be 40–50 years old.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>fish
        <name>American Black (Largemouth) Bass</name>
        <scientific>Micropterus salmoides</scientific>
        <id>6</id>
        <Habitat>Micropterus salmoides is native to eastern North America and historically ranged from southern Canada to northern Mexico, and from the Atlantic coast to the central region of the United States. Since the beginning of the twentieth century largemouth bass have been introduced successfully all over the world.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Micropterus salmoides has a large mouth, a notch between the two dorsal fins, and a dark stripe along the side of the body (Bailey et al., 2004). This black band is seemingly made up of small oval shapes to a closer eye. Coloration is variable, but is usually a darkish green on the back and sides, fading to an off-white on the belly. The anterior dorsal fin has nine to eleven spines while the posterior dorsal fin has twelve to fourteen rays. The average weight of M. salmoides is one kilogram; however, certain individuals have reached weights of over ten kilograms. Males usually do not surpass 40 cm, while females can reach up to 56 cm in length.</Physical>
        <Diet>Immature Micropterus salmoides feed on zooplankton and aquatic insects. As they grow their diet shifts to crayfish and other fish species. Sunfish are the food of choice for most adult largemouth bass.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Largemouth bass live much longer in the wild than they do in captivity. The longest known lifespan of a wild largemouth bass was 23 years. The expected lifespan in the wild, though, is around 15 years. In captivity the longest lifespan recorded was 11 years, while the average age of death in captivity is around 6 years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>fish
        <name>Common (Spotted) Seahorse</name>
        <scientific>Hippocampus kuda</scientific>
        <id>7</id>
        <Habitat>Hippocampus kuda is strictly a marine species, widely distributed throughout the Indo-Pacific region, from the Indian Ocean to the northwestern, western central, and eastern central areas of the Pacific Ocean. Approximately 23 countries have confirmed the native presence of H. kuda, ranging from Australia to China (Lourie et al., 2004). Because spotted seahorses are popular ornamental aquarium fish, their captive distribution has become global.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Seahorse lengths are measured by recording the distance from the tip of the tail to the top of the coronet, a cup-like depression found on top of the head. Adult lengths of H. kuda typically range between 7.0 and 17.0 cm. Adult weights, on the other hand, vary with the reproductive stages of both males and females.</Physical>
        <Diet>Spotted seahorses are ambush predators and thrive only on live, moving food. They have large appetites and feed mainly on zooplankton, small crustaceans, and larval fishes. Because they are poor swimmers, H. kuda utilize their thick snouts and specialized jaws to suck in their prey</Diet>
        <Lifespan>The natural lifespan of H. kuda and its relatives are virtually unknown. Lab and aquatic observations estimate 3 to 5 years for larger seahorse species and 1 year for smaller species.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>fish
        <name>Alfred manta (Reef Manta) (Manta Ray) </name>
        <scientific>Manta alfredi</scientific>
        <id>8</id>
        <Habitat>Reef manta rays are found primarily in the Indian and Pacific Oceans, including coastal waters surrounding Australia, Japan, South Africa, Thailand and Hawaii, as well as the Red Sea. Although they have been found in the Atlantic Ocean, such sightings are rare. Reef manta rays are a marine species found in inshore habitats (within a few kilometers of land) in tropical and subtropical latitudes. They are often sighted near coral and rocky reefs in atolls and bays, likely due to the high densities of zooplankton associated with these areas. While it is known that they tend to avoid deep or open waters, the exact depth range in which they can be found is uncertain.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Reef manta rays have wing-like pectoral fins and cephalic fin tips, or horns, that wrap around the mouth. Their central body disc is approximately two times longer than it is broad, with an average width of approximately 390 cm for adult females and 300 cm for adult males. The largest recorded specimen measured 550 cm in width. This is much smaller than giant manta rays (Manta birostris), a closely related species, which seldom measure smaller than 550 cm at maturity. Reef manta rays have a slender tail, with no distinct caudal spine. They are black in color dorsally and cream or white colored ventrally. A diagnostic feature of their coloration is the presence of light colored patches on the shoulder region, contrasting with the overall dark dorsal surface. Both the dorsal and ventral surfaces are covered in knob-like denticles, which are evenly distributed; ventral denticles are larger. They have a total of 918-1456 small, cusped teeth, which are each 1-2 mm in length. Reef manta rays are sexually dimorphic.</Physical>
        <Diet>Reef manta rays are planktivores, feeding exclusively on zooplankton. When feeding, their cephalic horns are extended and their swimming becomes more deliberate. Plankton is filtered using the ventrally located gill slits. Reef manta rays follow the tidal changes that concentrate zooplankton in shallower atoll channels, increasing feeding rates.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Re-sightings of individuals (identified by unique patterns of spots around their gill slits) have been recorded for spans of up to thirty years. It is estimated that this species may live at least forty years in the wild. While mortality rates are high in juveniles, adult mortality is low, probably due to their large size and a lack of predators.</Lifespan>
    </item>



    <item>mammal
        <name>Giraffe</name>
        <scientific>Giraffa camelopardalis</scientific>
        <id>1</id>
        <Habitat>Giraffes inhabits arid, dry land. They seek out areas enriched with Acacia growth. Giraffes are found in savannas, grasslands, or open woodlands. Because they only occasionally drink, giraffes can be found away from a water source. Male giraffes can venture into denser wooded areas in search of more foliage.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Giraffa camelopardalis is the world’s tallest mammal. Male giraffes (bulls) stand a total of 5.7 m from the ground to their horns: 3.3 m at the shoulders with a long neck of 2.4 m. Female giraffes (cows) are 0.7 to 1 m shorter than bulls. Bulls weigh up to 1,930 kg, while cows can weigh up to 1,180 kg. At birth, giraffe calves are 2 m tall from the ground to the shoulders. Newborn giraffes weigh 50 to 55 kg.</Physical>
        <Diet>Giraffes feed on leaves, flowers, seed pods, and fruits. In areas where the savanna floor is salty or full of minerals, they eat soil as well. Giraffes are ruminants and have a four-chambered stomach. Chewing cud while traveling helps to maximize their feeding opportunities.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Giraffa camelopardalis have a life expectancy between 20 to 27 years in zoos. Giraffes live for 10 to 15 years in the wild.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>mammal
        <name>African Bush Elephant</name>
        <scientific>Loxodonta africana</scientific>
        <id>2</id>
        <Habitat>The habitats occupied by African elephants vary because they can survive long periods of time without water; they occupy deserts, forests, savannas, river valleys and marshes.</Habitat>
        <Physical>African elephants are the heaviest land animal, and the second tallest in the Animal Kingdom. They are a sexually dimorphic species; males appear larger than females. The height of a bull at his shoulder is about twelve feet (about 3.75 m), when the female’s height is nine feet (about 3 m). They have enormous ears, each measuring about four feet (120-125 cm) across. They have a unique nose that is simply a long, boneless trunk extending from the upper lip. The trunk usually measures about five feet long (about 150 cm) and weighs around 300 pounds (about 135 kg).</Physical>
        <Diet>Elephants eat vegetation like leaves, roots, bark, grasses and fruit. Each day they can consume anywhere from 220 to 660 pounds (100 to 300 kg) of food, and drink up to 50 gallons (190 L) of water. During the rainy seasons elephants eat grass and herbs like papyrus (Cyperus papyrus) and cat tails (Typha augustifolia). During dry seasons in the savannah they eat leaves collected from thorny trees and bushes. Swamps are a last resort for food because swamp vegetation contains little nutrition. However, dying elephants are often found in these areas because this vegetation is softer and older elephants are often missing teeth.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Elephants have one of the longest lifespans of all mammals- about seventy years. Their age can be determined by height comparison to the matriarch, tusk length, or more complicated methods like measuring the weight of an eye lens from an elephant that recently died. Aging elephants faces appear sunken and their ears fold toward their body as they get older. They may also suffer from arthritis, tuberculosis or blood diseases like septicemea. Accidental death can occur if an elephant falls down a hill, or if it loses a fight with another elephant. Deaths from poaching still outnumber any natural or accidental occurrences of death in elephants.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>mammal
        <name>Arctic Fox</name>
        <scientific>Vulpes lagopus</scientific>
        <id>3</id>
        <Habitat>Arctic foxes are found in the treeless tundra extending through the arctic regions of Eurasia, North America, Greenland, and Iceland. Arctic foxes are found mainly in arctic and alpine tundra, usually in coastal areas.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Arctic foxes have beautiful white (sometimes blue-gray) coats that act as very effective winter camouflage. The natural hues allow the animal to blend into the tundra's ubiquitous snow and ice. When the seasons change, the fox's coat turns as well, adopting a brown or gray appearance that provides cover among the summer tundra's rocks and plants.</Physical>
        <Diet>The arctic fox is an opportunistic feeder, eating practically any animal, alive or dead. Although it prefers small mammals, it will eat insects, berries, carrion, and even the stool of animals or human beings. Generally, its winter diet consists of marine mammals, invertebrates, sea birds, fish, and seals. For populations living more inland and in the summer, the diet consists mostly of lemmings. During the summer months, when food is much more readily available, arctic foxes collect a surplus amount of food and carries it back to their dens, where it is stored under stones for later use.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Arctic Foxes have an average lifespan of 16.3 years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>mammal
        <name>South American Squirrel Monkey</name>
        <scientific>Saimiri sciureus</scientific>
        <id>4</id>
        <Habitat>Squirrel monkeys live in the tropical rainforests of South America, except in the southeastern coastal forests of Brazil. Squirrel monkeys prefer primary and secondary forest, gallery forest and forest edge. They prefer the intermediate forest levels, but they can sometimes be found on the ground or in upper canopy levels. They occupy many different types of forests.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Squirrel monkeys are up to 12.5 inches long (body length), with a tail of approximately 16 inches. They have a slender, lithe build, with a short greyish coat and bright yellow legs. Their non-prehensile tail often curls over one shoulder when they are resting. They have 36 teeth, and their teeth are sexually dimorphic in that males have large upper canines. Squirrel monkesy possess nails instead of claws, and they have been called 'small, nervous primates'. They are the smallest of the Primate family Cebidae.</Physical>
        <Diet>Squirrel monkeys eat mainly fruit and some insects; they also consume some leaves and seeds. The first hour or so of the day is spent searching and collecting fruit. From then on, they look also for spiders and insects. A group spreads throughout the forest in all canopy levels to search for food.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>The average lifespan of a South American Squirrel Monkey is 21 years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>mammal
        <name>Red Kangaroo</name>
        <scientific>Macropus rufus</scientific>
        <id>5</id>
        <Habitat>Macropus rufus occurs over most of the dry, inland, central part of Australia. This expansive area includes scrubland, shrubland, grassland, and desert habitats. Red kangaroos live over most of the central part of Australia in areas where rainfall averages less than 500 millimeters. They prefer to forage in open plains habitats with neither trees nor bushes, but are seldom found in regions without shade and shelter from scattered trees.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Macropus rufus is the largest living marsupial. Males range in total body length from 1,300 to 1,600 mm and females from 850 to 1,050 mm. Tail length is from 1,000 to 1,200 mm for males and 650 to 850 mm for females. They may weigh as much as 90 kg and may reach 1.8 meters in height when standing. Coat color is usually reddish brown in males and bluish gray in females, although these colors are reversed in some areas, with females being reddish and males blue-gray. Red kangaroos are robustly built, with large, well-muscled tails and powerful hindquarters. The tail is strong enough to support the kangaroo's body weight, acts as a balance when jumping, and is used, with the two legs, to form a tripod for resting. The second and third toes of red kangaroos are fused and shaped into a grooming claw. Their foreshortened upper limbs terminate in clawed paws used with great dexterity in eating, grooming, and self-defense. Females have a forward facing pouch and 4 mammae.</Physical>
        <Diet>Red kangaroos are exclusively plant-eaters, with a preferred diet of green herbage including grasses and dicotyledonous flowering plants. These herbivores can go without water for long periods of time by consuming moisture-filled succulent plants.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Lifespans are potentially long in red kangaroos, although most individuals probably do not survive their first year of life. Red kangaroos have been recorded living up to 22 years in the wild.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>mammal
        <name>Duck-billed Platypus</name>
        <scientific>Ornithorhynchus anatinus</scientific>
        <id>6</id>
        <Habitat>The geographic range of Ornithorhynchus anatinus is restricted to the wetter regions of eastern Australia and Tasmania.Duck-billed platypuses inhabit rivers, lagoons, and streams. They prefer areas with steep banks that contain roots, overhanging vegetation, reeds, and logs. The rivers and streams are usually less than 5 meters in depth. There have been records of them living in aquatic habitats at elevations above 1000 meters.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Duck-billed platypuses are one of three species of monotremes. These species are unique among mammals in that they retain the ancestral characteristic of egg laying. They have a cloaca through which eggs are laid and both liquid and solid waste is eliminated. Duck-billed platypuses are stream-lined and elongated, they have fur ranging from medium brown to dark brown on the dorsal side and brown to silver-gray on the ventral side. They have bills that closely resemble those of ducks, and flat and broad tails resembling those of beavers. Two nostrils are located on top of their bills and their eyes and ears are on either side of their heads. They have short limbs, naked soles, webbed forefeet and partially-webbed hind feet. Each foot contains five digits each consisting of a broad nail for the forefeet and sharp claws for the hind feet. Males are generally larger than females, and have two venom glands attached to spurs on their hind legs. Females have mammary glands but no nipples. The young have milk teeth while the adults have grinding plates. The young are smaller than adults in size. There is a significant reduction in body fat after winter for both young and adults</Physical>
        <Diet>Duck-billed platypuses eat primarily aquatic invertebrates in streams and lakes. They also eat shrimp, fish eggs, and small fish.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>There is little information on the longevity of duck-billed platypuses. They can live up to 12 years in the wild.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>mammal
        <name>Bottlenosed Dolphin</name>
        <scientific>Tursiops truncatus</scientific>
        <id>7</id>
        <Habitat>Tursiops truncatus typically occupies waters with surface temperatures between 50 and 90 degrees Fahrenheit. Although some bottlenosed dolphins migrate seasonally (for example, populations along the Atlantic coast), they are typically found in tropical, subtropical, and warm temperate waters.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Bottlenosed dolphins have a fusiform body that lacks many external characteristics of terrestrial mammals, including hair, external ears and hind limbs. A fusiform body reduces turbulence and allows bottlenosed dolphins to cruise underwater at high speeds. Dolphins have front flippers, a dorsal fin and flukes, which are used in swimming. The dorsal fin is tall, curved and set near the middle of the back. These dolphins are typically black to a light gray on their sides, and their bellies are white, sometimes with a slight pink hue. Bottlenosed dolphins are typically 84 to 140 cm at birth, and typically weigh between 14 and 20 kg. Adult males are usually between 244 and 381 cm long, and weigh about 500 kg. Adult females are typically between 228 and 366 cm, and weigh about 250 kg. This sexual dimorphism may be a result of females using energy to achieve sexual maturity at a earlier age than males, while males continue to grow.</Physical>
        <Diet>The diet of bottlenosed dolphins is broad and varies from one place to another. Inshore bottlenosed dolphins typically feed on fish and invertebrates found near the shoreline, while deep water bottlenosed dolphins typically feed on squid and pelagic fish. Bottlenosed dolphins found along the U.S. Atlantic coast typically feed on Atlantic croakers (Micropogonias undulatus), ‘spot’ fish (Leistomomus xanthurus), and silver perch (Bairdiella chrysoura), while dolphins in South Africa typically feed on African massbankers (Trachurus delagoae), olive grunters (Pomadasys olivaceus), and pandora (Pagellus bellotti). Bottlenosed dolphins typically choose prey between 5 and 30 cm in length. They eat between 4.5 and 16 kg per day, depending on the size of the individual and if it is lactating.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Bottlenosed dolphins are threatened by a variety of factors, both natural and of human origin. Natural mortality is due to injury, disease, and predation. Male bottlenosed dolphins typically live about 40 to 45 years and female dolphins can live over 50 years (the oldest female documented lived to be 53 years old). Because in many cases dolphins are found in shallow waters, they encounter many humans and human activities. Recreational fishing gear causes many deaths when dolphins become entangled in nets or swallow fishing hooks. Dolphins are sometimes preyed upon by sharks, although this is may be less of a problem now than in the past due to declining shark populations. One of the largest and most serious threats to bottlenosed dolphins is environmental contamination, caused mainly by the increase of human development along shorelines. Chemicals of human origin find their way into coastal ecosystems through runoff from agriculture, residential, and industrial sources.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>mammal
        <name>American Black Bear</name>
        <scientific>Ursus americanus</scientific>
        <id>8</id>
        <Habitat>Black bears can be found from northern Alaska east across Canada to Labrador and Newfoundland, and south through much of Alaska, virtually all of Canada, and most of the U.S. into central Mexico.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Black bears are usually black in color, particularly in eastern North America. They usually have a pale muzzle which contrasts with their darker fur and may sometimes have a white chest spot. Western populations are usually lighter in color, being more often brown, cinnamon, or blonde. Some populations in coastal British Columbia and Alaska are creamy white or bluish gray. Total body length in males ranges from 1400 to 2000 mm, and from 1200 to 1600 mm in females. Tail length ranges from 80 to 140 mm. Males weigh between 47 and 409 kg, females weigh between 39 and 236 kg. The distance between the canine teeth is about 4.5 to 5 cm.</Physical>
        <Diet>Throughout their range in North America, black bears consume primarily grasses and forbs in spring, soft mast in the form of shrub and tree-borne fruits in summer, and a mixture of hard and soft mast in fall. However, the availability of different food types varies regionally. Only a small portion of the diet of bears consists of animal matter, and then primarily in the form of colonial insects and beetles. Most vertebrates are consumed in the form of carrion. Black bears are not active predators and feed on vertebrates only if the opportunity exists.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Black bears can live to 30 years in the wild but most often live for only about 10, mostly because of encounters with humans. More than 90% of black bear deaths after the age of 18 months are the result of gunshots, trapping, motor vehicle accidents, or other interactions with humans.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>reptile
        <name>Common Green Iguana</name>
        <scientific>Iguana iguana</scientific>
        <id>1</id>
        <Habitat>Green iguanas, Iguana iguana, occur throughout Central and South America, from Sinaloa and Veracruz, Mexico, south to the Tropic of Capricorn in Paraguay and southeast Brazil. This large lizard also inhabits many islands throughout the Caribbean region and the coastal eastern Pacific, and has been introduced into southern Florida and in Hawaii. This is the largest known lizard to occur within the borders of the United States.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Within three years, a young, 12 gram hatchling iguana can become a 1 kg adult (de Vosjoli, 1992). Upon hatching, the length of green iguanas ranges from 17 to 25 cm. Most mature iguanas weigh between 4 and 6 kg, but some in South America, with proper diet can reach up to 8 kg. These large lizards can reach head to tail lengths of around 2 m.</Physical>
        <Diet>Green iguanas are primarily herbivorous. They occasionally eat a small amount of carrion or invertebrates. Green leafy plants or ripe fruits are their preferred foods.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Iguanas can live for more than 20 years in captivity, although wild iguanas are thought to live only about 8 years. Proper nutrition for growth is a concern for captive management of these animals. Improper housing and nutrition can shorten a captive iguana's lifespan.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>reptile
        <name>Komodo Dragon</name>
        <scientific>Varanus komodoensis</scientific>
        <id>2</id>
        <Habitat>Varanus komodoensis is found only in the lesser Sunda region of the Indonesian archipelago, including the islands of Komodo, Flores, Rinca, and Padar. Adult Komodo dragons live mainly in tropical savannah forests. They prefer open lowland areas with tall grasses and bushes, but are also found in other habitats, such as beaches, ridge tops, and dry riverbeds. Young Komodo dragons are arboreal and live in forested regions until they are eight months old.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Komodo dragons are the largest lizards, reaching 165 kg and greater than three meters in length. Juveniles are green with yellow and black bands. Adults dull and uniform in color, from brown to grayish red. Their robust bodies are uniformly covered in rough scales. They have strong limbs and a powerful, muscular tail. The heads of Komodo dragons have a rounded snout and ear openings. Their skulls are flexible and have sharp, serrated teeth. Although males tend to grow larger, there are no obvious morphological differences between the sexes.</Physical>
        <Diet>A normal adult Komodo dragon diet consists mainly of carrion, but it is not uncommon for them to attack and eat a variety of large prey, including goats, pigs, deer, wild boar, horses, water buffalo, and smaller Komodo dragons. Komodo dragons hunt larger prey by ambushing them and delivering a bite. They then follow the injured animal until they succumb to either blood loss or infection. The saliva of Komodo dragons is rich in bacteria that rapidly leads to infection in their prey.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Although many Varanus komodoensis individuals fall prey to other animals as hatchlings, ones that live to adulthood usually have a lifespan of around 50 years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>reptile
        <name>Leopard Tortoise</name>
        <scientific>Psammobates pardalis</scientific>
        <id>3</id>
        <Habitat>Leopard tortoises occupy a variety of xeric and mesic habitats throughout their geographic range, ranging from dry arid plains to temperate grassland ecosystems. They are intolerant of damp or cold habitats. They have also been reported in mountainous terrain. These tortoises spend most of their time in shrub habitat with low lying vegetation, which serves as their primary food source. In the summer, they seek shelter under various low lying plants.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Leopard tortoises are the fourth largest tortoise species in the world. They exhibit indeterminate growth and adults range in mass from 15 to 54 kg, with an average of 18 kg. Carapace length ranges from 30 to 70 cm, with an average carapace length of 45 cm. Females are often larger than males. It also is common for leopard tortoises to have moderate carapacial pyramiding, a shell deformity in which scutes exhibit pyramidal growth.</Physical>
        <Diet>Leopard tortoises are primarily herbivorous, with plant material making up approximately 98% of their diet. They consume berries and other fruits when available. Bone fragments and ash may be consumed during times of decreased resource abundance. Although most tortoises consume mostly grasses, leopard tortoises primarily consume forbs. They feed primarily from the ground, particularly from areas within their habitat that produce low-lying forbs.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>In the wild, adult leopard tortoises may live for up to 100 years. No records are available regarding captive individuals. However, typical lifespan for other species of Geochelone tortoises in captivity is approximately 50 years. Factors that may limit the lifespan of leopard tortoises include human impacts through the pet trade and male aggression during courtship and mating.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>reptile
        <name>King Cobra</name>
        <scientific>Ophiophagus hannah</scientific>
        <id>4</id>
        <Habitat>Northern India, east to southern People's Republic of China, including Hong Kong and Hainan; south throughout the Malay Peninsula, and east to western Indonesia and the Philippines.They live near streams in dense or open forest, bamboo thickets, adjacent agricultural areas, and dense mangrove swamps.</Habitat>
        <Physical>The King Cobra's average size is 10-12 feet, but can reach 18 feet. The full grown King Cobra is yellow, green, brown, or black. There are usually yellowish or white cross-bars or chevrons on its body. The belly may be uniform in color or ornamented with bars. The throat is light yellow or cream-colored. The juveniles are jet-black, with yellow or white cross-bars on the body and tail and four similar cross-bars on the head. The King Cobra is regarded as a fierce and aggressive snake, and its length and size give it an awesome appearance.</Physical>
        <Diet>Ophiophagus hannah normally restricts its diet to cold-blooded animals, particularly other snakes. Some specimens develop a rigid diet of a single species of snake and will refuse any other type. The snakes eaten by the King Cobra are mostly the larger harmless species, such as Asian rat snakes, dhamans, and pythons up to about 10 feet in length.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>The average King Cobra will live 17.1 years in captivity.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>reptile
        <name>Collared Lizard</name>
        <scientific>Crotaphytus collaris</scientific>
        <id>5</id>
        <Habitat>C. collaris inhabit rocky areas with sparse vegetation. Boulder strewn hillsides and rocky outcroppings are common in their living areas. Collared lizards dig under boulders to sleep and lay their eggs</Habitat>
        <Physical>Colors and markings are diverse in Crotaphytus collaris. They are sexually dimorphic. Males tend to be green to tan colored with patterns of dorsal spots and bars to a speckled pattern across the dorsum. Male C. collaris can also exhibit vivid yellow and orange head coloration. Female C. collaris tend to be less colorful except during breeding season when they exhibit bright orange side spots or bars. Both male and female C. collaris possess two prominent collar-like black bands at their neck, hence their name.</Physical>
        <Diet>Crotaphytus collaris is mainly insectivorous and carnivorous. Occasionally their diet may consist of plant matter. C. collaris does vary its diet depending on what is abundant. Food can range from grasshoppers to smaller lizards.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Collared lizards' life span ranges from 10 to 15 years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>reptile
        <name>American Alligator</name>
        <scientific>Alligator mississippiensis</scientific>
        <id>6</id>
        <Habitat>American alligators are found from the southern Virginia-North Carolina border, along the Atlantic coast to Florida and along the Gulf of Mexico as far west as the Rio Grande in Texas. American alligators are usually found in freshwater swamps, marshes, rivers, lakes, and occasionally, smaller bodies of water. It is believed that this preference for calm waters has to do with their swimming and breathing.</Habitat>
        <Physical>The average size for an adult female is just under 3 meters (9.8 feet), while the adult male usually falls between 4 and 4.5 meters (13 to 14.7 feet). American alligators reaching lengths of 5-6 meters (16 to 20 feet) have been reported in the past, but there have been no recent recordings equaling those lengths.</Physical>
        <Diet>Alligators are basically carnivores, but they eat more than just meat, feeding on anything from sticks to fishing lures to aluminum cans. Mostly, they consume fish, turtles, snakes, and small mammals. When they are young they feed on insects, snails, and small fish.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>While there are currently no methods for determining the age of an alligator while still alive, it is known that those in the wild tend to live to between 35 and 50 year, while those in captive generally live longer, around 65-80 years. Factors which can lead to earlier mortality include successful predation early in life and hunting by humans.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>reptile
        <name>Eastern Diamondback Rattlesnake</name>
        <scientific>Crotalus adamanteus</scientific>
        <id>7</id>
        <Habitat>The Eastern Diamondback lives in the coastal lowlands, ranging from southeast North Carolina to eastern Louisiana, and throughout Florida, including the Florida Keys. The Eastern Diamondback resides in the palmetto flatwoods and dry pinelands of the South. It generally avoids marshes and swamps, but on occasion will live near the borders of wetlands. Occasionally it may venture into salt water, swimming to the outlying Keys off the Florida coast.</Habitat>
        <Physical>The Eastern diamondback is one of the largest North American snakes, with a record length of 8 feet. However, they are usually 33 to 72 inches in length. The snake has a large head and a bulky body. It has a row of large dark diamonds with brown centers and cream borders down its back. The ground color of the body ranges from olive, to brown, to almost black. The tail is usually a different shade, brownish or gray, and banded with dark rings. At the end of the tail is a well-developed rattle.</Physical>
        <Diet>The Eastern diamondback feeds primarily on small mammals, from mice to rabbits. It will also eat birds. Young diamondbacks feed primarily on rats and mice, while adults prefer larger prey like rabbits and squirrels. The snakes lie waiting for prey beside logs or near the roots of fallen trees. Diamondbacks locate their prey by odor, as well as by sensing the infrared waves (heat) given off by their warm-blooded prey. Once found, the prey is bitten. The prey is released after the strike, and is then allowed to crawl away and die. The snake will pursue the prey, eating it once it is dead.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>The average Diamondback lives to be 22.8 years in captivity.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>reptile
        <name>Common Snapping Turtle</name>
        <scientific>Chelydra serpentina</scientific>
        <id>8</id>
        <Habitat>The snapping turtle's range stretches from S. Alberta and east to Nova Scotia in the north, extending south all the way to the Gulf of Mexico and into central Texas. Snapping turtles only live in fresh or brackish water. They prefer water bodies with muddy bottoms and abundant vegetation because concealment is easier.</Habitat>
        <Physical>The snapping turtle normally has a shell length ranging from 8 -18 1/2"and has a tail nearly as long as the shell. The tail has saw-toothed keels on it. The shell ranges in color from dark brown to tan and can even be black in some individuals. Snapping turtles have characteristic tubercles on their necks and legs. Plastrons of snapping turtles are very small and leave much of the extremities exposed. Snapping turtle necks, legs, and tails have a yellowish color and the head is dark in color.</Physical>
        <Diet>Snapping turtles will eat nearly anything that they can get their jaws around. They feed on carrion, invertebrates, fish, birds, small mammals, amphibians, and a surprisingly large amount of aquatic vegetation. Snapping turtles kill other turtles by decapitation. This behavior might be territoriality towards other turtles or a very inefficient feeding behavior.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>In the wild snapping turtles are estimated to live up to 30 years. Snapping turtles are most vulnerable as hatchlings. Once they reach a certain size there are few natural predators of snapping turtles, though they are often hit by cars when searching for new ponds or nesting sites. In captivity they can live up to 47 years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
</animals>