<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<animals>
    <item>
        <type>fish</type>
        <name>Common Clownfish</name>
        <scientific>Amphiprion ocellaris</scientific>
        <id>1</id>
        <Habitat>Amphiprion ocellaris inhabits coral reefs (Allen 1997) and sheltered lagoons up to a depth of 15 meters. More specifically, it is mainly found in or near the anemones Heteractis magnifica, Stichodactyla gigantean, and Stichodactyla mertensii (Myers 1999) as part of a symbiotic relationship.</Habitat>
        <Physical>False clownfish are orange to reddish-brown with three white bands on the head and body. The white bands are outlined in black. Black A. ocellaris, with white bands and black coloring instead of orange, are found off the Northern Territory of Australia. Amphiprion ocellaris has a rounded caudal fin and may grow up to 110 mm in length. There are 11 dorsal spines and 17 pectoral rays that help to distinguish it from the closely related Amphiprion percula. Females are larger than males in this species. </Physical>
        <Diet>Planktonic food such as zooplankton, copepods, and algae are the primary source of food for A. ocellaris. They are classified as generalized omnivores as they feed on equal amounts of algae and animals. They are also reported to consume parasites from their host anemones. Feeding is also dominated by the hierarchical structure of the group dynamics in the anemone. Because the smaller fish receive the most aggression from the others, they have reduced energy for foraging great distances from the anemone and tend to stay close. Additionally, it is unsafe for the smaller fish to stray farther from the safety of the anemone. The large, dominant fish will forage at greater distances, but generally no farther than several meters from the anemone.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Lifespan has not been studied fully in the wild, but it is believed that A. ocellaris may live 6-10 years. Larval fish are extremely susceptible to predation as they have no way of defending themselves and have high mortality rates. Captivity transfer experiments have been performed to address the possibility of restocking the fish in areas where they have been depleted; these find that survival among transferred fish is higher among smaller A. ocellaris.</Lifespan>
    </item>

    <item>
        <type>fish</type>
        <name>Tiger Shark</name>
        <scientific>Galeocerdo cuvier</scientific>
        <id>2</id>
        <Habitat>Tiger sharks are found in many subtropical and tropical waters, primarily from 45°N to 32°S. Tiger sharks have been sighted from the eastern coast of North America to the eastern coast of Brazil. This includes the coasts of southern North America, Mexico, and Latin America along the Gulf of Mexico. Tiger sharks also populate the coasts of China, India, Africa, Japan, and many islands of the Pacific Ocean.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Tiger sharks are one of the largest carnivores in the ocean. Juveniles have tiger-like stripes, which fade as they grow older. Tiger sharks are blue or green in color with a light yellow or white under-belly. This speices has a large blunt nose on the end of a wedge-shaped head. Tiger sharks have serrated teeth, making it easy to tear flesh and crack the bones and shells of their prey. They have a heterocercal tail, meaning the dorsal lobe of the caudal fin is longer than the ventral lobe. Adults range from 3.25 to 4.25 m in length, although tiger sharks of 6 to 7.5 m in length have been documented. Female tiger sharks are on average 2.92 m in length and are smaller than males, which are on average 3.20 m in length. Adult tiger sharks typically weigh 385 to 635 kg, with largest sharks reaching 862 kg.</Physical>
        <Diet>The diet of tiger sharks includes mollusks, birds, snakes, crustaceans, sea turtles, and dugongs. Serrated teeth give this species the ability to penetrate the shells of sea turtles. Tiger sharks often scavenge dead or injured whales, and large tiger sharks can survive several weeks without feeding. This species most likely relies on stealth rather than strength and speed to catch prey. They are well camouflaged, allowing them to get within striking range of prey. If prey flee, tiger sharks may back off, not taking part in high-speed pursuits. However, tiger sharks are capable of short bursts of speed once their prey are within range.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>The average lifespan of tiger sharks in the wild is 27 years, though some may live to 50 years of age. Tiger sharks in captivity do not live as long, a maximum of 17 to 20 years. In captivity, this species tends to die of starvation rather than old age, as food that is already dead is less appealing to tiger sharks.</Lifespan>
    </item>

    <item>
        <type>fish</type>
        <name>Redbelly Piranha</name>
        <scientific>Pygocentrus nattereri</scientific>
        <id>3</id>
        <Habitat>Pygocentrus nattereri is found in South America. Pygocentrus nattereri can be found east of the Andes in the Parana-Paraguay and Amazon basin. They can also be found in rivers of northeast Brazil and the Guianas.They are typically found in whitewater streams in South America. However, the species is not found typically in blackwater streams</Habitat>
        <Physical>Pygocentrus nattereri physical characteristics vary with location, population, and age. In juvenile P. nattereri there are differences in physical characteristics depending on the size of the fish. A change in color pattern does seem to develop as size increases. The thickening body tissue tends to cause the black internal line of the anal fin to disappear and both the number of body spots and the density of melanophores increases with growth. Adult specimens also tend to vary in color pattern and body size with geographic location. Generally P. nattereri is reddish-orange ventrally and silver-gray dorsally. The fins vary in color as well, with a black dorsal fin, black anal fin, and reddish-orange pectoral fins. The lateral color of the fish is a gray to silver- gray.</Physical>
        <Diet>Foraging methods vary in different life stages of P. nattereri. During the day, smaller fish (80-110 mm) search for food. At dawn, late afternoon, and early evening the larger fish (150-240 mm) search for food. Pygocentrus nattereri groups gather in vegetation in order to wait for prey. The group typically includes around 20-30 fishes. In the daytime P. nattereri can be seen lurking or ambushing prey. Two other methods for obtaining food employed by P. nattereri are chasing and scavenging. The hunting mode of chasing was seen after the fish lie and wait in vegetation. The fish then proceed to swim after and eat the fish. P. nattereri has a wide variety of food in its diet, including fins, scales, fish (pieces and whole), insects, snails, and plants. The plant intake of the animal may be an active way of gaining food supplies while scanning for prey.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Piranhas can live up to eight years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>
        <type>fish</type>
        <name>Atlantic Sailfish</name>
        <scientific>Istiophorus platypterus</scientific>
        <id>4</id>
        <Habitat>Indo-Pacific sailfish (Istiophorus platypterus) can be found in both temperate and tropical waters throughout the world's oceans. They generally have a tropical distribution and are particularly abundant near the equatorial regions of the Atlantic, Pacific, and Indian Oceans from 45° to 50° N in the western North Pacific and from 35° to 40° N in the eastern North Pacific to approximately 35° S in the eastern South Pacific. In the western Indian Ocean and in the eastern Indian Ocean, Indo-Pacific sailfish range between 45° to 35° S, respectively. This species is essentially found along the coastal regions of these latitudes, but can also be found in the central regions of these oceans.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Trophy specimens of Indo-Pacific sailfish have measured up to 340 cm, weighing as much as 100 kg. Their fusiform body is long, compressed, and remarkably streamlined. Indo-Pacific sailfish are dark blue dorsally, with a mix of brown and light blue laterally, and a silver-white color on their ventral side. This coloration is a form of obliterative countershading. This species is easily distinguished from other billfish by the approximately 20 stripes of light blue dots present along their lateral sides. Their head bears a long bill and jaws filled with file-like teeth. Their massive first dorsal fin is sail-like, with 42 to 49 rays, with a much smaller second dorsal fin, with 6 to 7 rays. The pectoral fins are long, stiff, and falcate in shape, bearing 18 to 20 rays. Pelvic fins are thoracic in position and up to 10 cm in length. Scale size decreases with maturity and scales are nearly absent in adults. Members of this species are exceptional swimmers, with a minute drag coefficient range of 0.0075 to 0.0091, which allows individuals to reach burst speeds of up to 110 km/hr. At cruising speeds of 11 km/hr, they can fold down their first dorsal fin to reduce drag.</Physical>
        <Diet>Typical foods of Indo-Pacific sailfish are epipelagic fish such as mackerels, sardines, and anchovies, as well as cephalopods. Sailfish been observed at cruising speeds with their dorsal fins folded back halfway in pursuit of prey. When sailfish attack a school of fish, they fold their fin back completely, achieving attack speeds of up to 110 km/hr. Once they approach their prey, they turn their bill quickly and hit the prey, stunning or killing it. Indo-Pacific sailfish either hunt alone or in small groups. Aside from hunting schools of small fish, Indo-Pacific sailfish are also opportunistic feeders, occasionally preying on neritic and benthic prey, a behavior similar to other billfish such as blue marlin, swordfish, and striped marlin. The particular species eaten by Indo-Pacific sailfish depend on the spatio-temporal distribution of their prey populations. Remnants of cephalopod and fish mandibles found in their stomachs suggest the rapid digestion of soft muscles.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Indo-Pacific sailfish have an estimated maximum lifespan of 13 to 15 years; however, the average age of catch and release specimens is 4 to 5 years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>
        <type>fish</type>
        <name>Great Hammerhead Shark</name>
        <scientific>Sphyrna mokarran</scientific>
        <id>5</id>
        <Habitat>Great hammerhead sharks occur in all tropical waters worldwide. These sharks are found in both open ocean and shallow coastal waters. During summer they may make small migrations towards more northerly areas.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Great hammerhead sharks posses a virtually straight anterior margin of the head with a deep central indentation. They have high second dorsal fins and the pelvic fins have curved rear margins. The teeth are triangular with extraordinarily serrated edges, becoming increasingly oblique toward the corners of the mouth. Their coloration varies from deep olive green to brownish grey above and white below. They are generally 4 to 6 m in length.</Physical>
        <Diet>Great hammerhead sharks feed on rays, smaller sharks, and many species of bony fishes.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>The typical lifespan of this species is 20–30 years; the record Boca Grande female was estimated to be 40–50 years old.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>
        <type>fish</type>
        <name>American Black (Largemouth) Bass</name>
        <scientific>Micropterus salmoides</scientific>
        <id>6</id>
        <Habitat>Micropterus salmoides is native to eastern North America and historically ranged from southern Canada to northern Mexico, and from the Atlantic coast to the central region of the United States. Since the beginning of the twentieth century largemouth bass have been introduced successfully all over the world.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Micropterus salmoides has a large mouth, a notch between the two dorsal fins, and a dark stripe along the side of the body (Bailey et al., 2004). This black band is seemingly made up of small oval shapes to a closer eye. Coloration is variable, but is usually a darkish green on the back and sides, fading to an off-white on the belly. The anterior dorsal fin has nine to eleven spines while the posterior dorsal fin has twelve to fourteen rays. The average weight of M. salmoides is one kilogram; however, certain individuals have reached weights of over ten kilograms. Males usually do not surpass 40 cm, while females can reach up to 56 cm in length.</Physical>
        <Diet>Immature Micropterus salmoides feed on zooplankton and aquatic insects. As they grow their diet shifts to crayfish and other fish species. Sunfish are the food of choice for most adult largemouth bass.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Largemouth bass live much longer in the wild than they do in captivity. The longest known lifespan of a wild largemouth bass was 23 years. The expected lifespan in the wild, though, is around 15 years. In captivity the longest lifespan recorded was 11 years, while the average age of death in captivity is around 6 years.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>
        <type>fish</type>
        <name>Common (Spotted) Seahorse</name>
        <scientific>Hippocampus kuda</scientific>
        <id>7</id>
        <Habitat>Hippocampus kuda is strictly a marine species, widely distributed throughout the Indo-Pacific region, from the Indian Ocean to the northwestern, western central, and eastern central areas of the Pacific Ocean. Approximately 23 countries have confirmed the native presence of H. kuda, ranging from Australia to China (Lourie et al., 2004). Because spotted seahorses are popular ornamental aquarium fish, their captive distribution has become global.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Seahorse lengths are measured by recording the distance from the tip of the tail to the top of the coronet, a cup-like depression found on top of the head. Adult lengths of H. kuda typically range between 7.0 and 17.0 cm. Adult weights, on the other hand, vary with the reproductive stages of both males and females.</Physical>
        <Diet>Spotted seahorses are ambush predators and thrive only on live, moving food. They have large appetites and feed mainly on zooplankton, small crustaceans, and larval fishes. Because they are poor swimmers, H. kuda utilize their thick snouts and specialized jaws to suck in their prey</Diet>
        <Lifespan>The natural lifespan of H. kuda and its relatives are virtually unknown. Lab and aquatic observations estimate 3 to 5 years for larger seahorse species and 1 year for smaller species.</Lifespan>
    </item>
    <item>
        <type>fish</type>
        <name>Alfred manta (Reef Manta) (Manta Ray) </name>
        <scientific>Manta alfredi</scientific>
        <id>8</id>
        <Habitat>Reef manta rays are found primarily in the Indian and Pacific Oceans, including coastal waters surrounding Australia, Japan, South Africa, Thailand and Hawaii, as well as the Red Sea. Although they have been found in the Atlantic Ocean, such sightings are rare. Reef manta rays are a marine species found in inshore habitats (within a few kilometers of land) in tropical and subtropical latitudes. They are often sighted near coral and rocky reefs in atolls and bays, likely due to the high densities of zooplankton associated with these areas. While it is known that they tend to avoid deep or open waters, the exact depth range in which they can be found is uncertain.</Habitat>
        <Physical>Reef manta rays have wing-like pectoral fins and cephalic fin tips, or horns, that wrap around the mouth. Their central body disc is approximately two times longer than it is broad, with an average width of approximately 390 cm for adult females and 300 cm for adult males. The largest recorded specimen measured 550 cm in width. This is much smaller than giant manta rays (Manta birostris), a closely related species, which seldom measure smaller than 550 cm at maturity. Reef manta rays have a slender tail, with no distinct caudal spine. They are black in color dorsally and cream or white colored ventrally. A diagnostic feature of their coloration is the presence of light colored patches on the shoulder region, contrasting with the overall dark dorsal surface. Both the dorsal and ventral surfaces are covered in knob-like denticles, which are evenly distributed; ventral denticles are larger. They have a total of 918-1456 small, cusped teeth, which are each 1-2 mm in length. Reef manta rays are sexually dimorphic.</Physical>
        <Diet>Reef manta rays are planktivores, feeding exclusively on zooplankton. When feeding, their cephalic horns are extended and their swimming becomes more deliberate. Plankton is filtered using the ventrally located gill slits. Reef manta rays follow the tidal changes that concentrate zooplankton in shallower atoll channels, increasing feeding rates.</Diet>
        <Lifespan>Re-sightings of individuals (identified by unique patterns of spots around their gill slits) have been recorded for spans of up to thirty years. It is estimated that this species may live at least forty years in the wild. While mortality rates are high in juveniles, adult mortality is low, probably due to their large size and a lack of predators.</Lifespan>
    </item>
</animals>